MUHAMMAD ASIM BAIG

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- 07897548769
- mabaig6610@gmail.com
- **♀** Gloucester, UK
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/muhammad-baig-6610/
- https://asimbaig.github.io/muhammad-asim-baig/

SKILLS



ABOUT ME

Committed and driven software developer with sound understanding & experience of software development and its life cycles. Keener to use best tools for task at hand.

I have abilities to utilize sound organizational and planning skills to deliver assignments within set time frames to high-quality.

Commercially I mostly work on full stack web projects in DotNet. I have used various JavaScript frameworks like NodeJS for RESTful API, ReactJs, Angular, jQuery and Ionic for front-end development. My other area of interest is data analysis using machine learning and Big Data.

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER CAM SYSTEMS LTD

September 2020 - Present

RESPONSBILITIES

- Maintaining existing applications by fixing bugs and adding new functionalities.
- ✓ Write clean, scalable code.
- ✓ Maintaining code using GitHub
- ✓ Practicing CI/CD using Microsoft Azure DevOps
- ✓ Team participation using Scrum framework.

WEB DEVELOPER CODEWEST

April 2019 - July 2019

RESPONSBILITIES

- Writing frontend application code, using Ionic and Angular
- Writing backend application code, using Nodejs (RESTful API) and MongoDB.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER THE DELTA GROUP

July 2019 - September 2020

RESPONSBILITIES

- Participate in requirements analysis and design.
- ✓ Write clean, scalable code.
- Revise, update, refactor and debug code.
- Remain up to date with the terminology, concepts, and best practices.
- Develop technical interfaces, specifications, and architecture.
- Use and adapt existing web applications.
- Create and test software prototypes.
- Develop client displays and user interfaces.
- Assist software personnel in handling project related work and other requirements.
- ✓ Coordinate with other teammates

SKILLS

6/10

MS SQL SERVER

6/10

MONGODB

EXPERIENCE

SELF EMPLOYEE

January 2013 - April 2019

WEB DEVELOPER

BEDROCK BUSINESS OUTSOURCING - PAKISTAN

January 2008 - June 2012

RESPONSBILITIES

- ✓ Maintaining performance of existing client web applications
- ✓ Suggesting improvements on design and functionality
- ✓ Diagnosing and rectifying performance issues
- Maintaining continuity throughout all websites both technically and creatively.
- Providing aftercare support for clients on assessing the performance of their sites.

EDUCATION

MSc-IT

University of West of England

2017-2019

MSc-IT

Preston University (Pakistan)

2006-2008

BSc-IT

Preston University (Pakistan)

2001-2005

FSc (Intermediate)

Govt. Model Degree College Lahore

1997-1999

AWARDS

Certified Scrum Master (January 2021)

Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE 8 Programmer (June 2016)

Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 8 Programmer (March 2016)

ACTIVITIES

Volunteer at events organisation for Bristol Asian community for last 4 years, also participated in teaching mathematics and basic computing to children in my local community in Pakistan.

REFERENCES

Will be furnished on demand.